

# ROBERT DEVINE IT SCIENTIST ENGINEER









# **EDUCATION**

## **Chemistry & Physics**

Villanova University
B.Sc, <u>SPS AIP</u> Honor Society

# **Engineering Science**

Penn State University
Data Architecture, Patterns

### **Regulatory Compliance**

Duke University Med School

### CDER, CBER, CDRH

FDA Badges: R Clinical Reporting, Drug Discovery - Graph Neural Network

# **SKILLS**

#### LANGUAGES SKILLS

R/Python/Julia/Haskell/C++

DevOps [Git | Kubernetes]

#### **SCIENTIFIC SKILLS**

**HPLC** 

Waters Empower, Alliance

Laboratory Software, DBA

#### **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

Work under Pressure

**Analytical Skills** 

Communication/Leadership

Multi-tasking

# **PROFILE**

Robert Devine is a Scientist and an Engineer deeply committed to the advancement of research in medicine. He is highly-experienced with engineering design patterns related to quality and scientific laboratory R&D in diverse settings from manufacturing industry to pharmaceuticals to the military.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Brand Owner, R&D Scientist**

2022-Present

SmartGxP™, Villanova, PA, United States

# Manufacturing R&D Laboratory Quality

- Net Total Care (SNTC) Portal and Common Service Platform Collector (CSPC).
- Responsible for customers consistently and surpassing goals quarter over quarter, utilizing Salesforce to track and communicate including Box.
- Focused on Customer Experience and Customer
   Success with advanced understanding of the Cisco and SAP portfolio, offers and teams.
- Updated and managed the Deployment Playbook to ensure Internal information is up-to-date.

Drive vision and commercialization of the SmartGxP<sup>TM</sup> brand. Inspire colleagues about *Quality*, *Regulatory Compliance*, *Formal Methods*, and *Automation* 

#### System Administrator / Manager

2022-2024

Manufacturing Logistics and Laboratory, Spring House, PA J&J/Janssen Deployed Intelligent Automation Solutions

- Automated Quotes to Support Lab Infrastructure
- Quality Framework Delivery GxP Change Mgmt.
- Focus on Customer Experience and Customer Success developing Productivity Toolsets

Ensured full compliance with JJT (Johnson & Johnson Technology) policies regarding SCM (Software Configuration Management) and Extensible Networked Laboratory Applications at Enterprise Scale



# ROBERT DEVINE IT SCIENTIST ENGINEER









#### HOBBIES

#### Reading

Travel





#### Health

**Antiques** 





# VOLUNTEERING

#### January 2014 - Present

American Institute of Physics, Serve as a Mentor

#### January 2021 - Present

R Consortium Working Group,

Serve as an Author and Contributor

#### March 2022 - Present

**AAPS** Screener

**Pharmaceutical Sciences** 

Serve as Screener for Paper/Posters Abstracts

#### October 2022 - Present

J&J HHS-TAP Awareness

New Jersey High Schools

Serve as SME for J&J

# **RECOGNITION**

#### United States Navy Total Quality Honoree [TQM]

Statistical Process Controls in Mfg.

**Gran Prix Level Dressage Owner** 

**Animal Rights Advocate** 

Fortune 500 Technology Educator

#### **United States Air Force**

Phase I-III SBIR Awards
-Complex Chalcogenide Tribology
Staff Scientist Role

# CONTINUED WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Enterprise Architect**

2014-2023

Xyntek [CXV Global], Inc., Newtown, PA, United States
On-boarded Global CRO/CDMO vendors for J&J/Janssen

- Originated highly-specialized Big Data | Unified Analytics Platform for Integrated Data Management
- Data Responsibility for 300+ scientists consistently.
- Integrated Data Management Data Architect, JJT
   SCM Platform Team Scientific Expert Data Science and Formal Methods, Semantic Ontology

Ensured full compliance with JJT (Johnson & Johnson Technology) policies regarding SCM (Software Configuration Management)

# **DevOps Skills**

- Kubernetes Full Stack Automation
- Greenfield Tanzu 2.x Kubernetes on AWS
- Unix/Linux administration
- Terraform and ARM Infrastructure Management
- Automation server (Jenkins JPM, GitLab)
- Manage full-lifecycle automation (SCM DevOps, Security)
- Cloud-based servers (AWS, Azure, GCP)
- Big Data Engines (Hadoop, Kafka, Spark, Impala)
- Apache Web Server, Nginx
- Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
  - (CI/CD) across Git long-life branches
- Programming languages
- .NET, Java, Python, Go, C++, Haskell, Bash, R, Julia, LINQ
- Enterprise Service Integration (Jira, ServiceNow)
- Microservices (Technical Debt, Governance, API)
- Agile methodology (Scrum, Kanban)
- AWS Controllers for Kubernetes [ACK]
- Zero-Trust Networks [ZTNA]
- Terraform Module Validation
- External Data Management of CRO/CDMO Vendors
- Intelligent Automation



# ROBERT DEVINE IT SCIENTIST ENGINEER









# TO:

SmartGxP<sup>™</sup> Colleagues January 25, 2024

# **Dear Colleagues and Visitors**

Thank you for taking time from your day to browse the SmartGxP<sup>TM</sup> brochure. If you have any questions please reach out through any of the digital contact points listed above. We offer highest-quality GxP laboratory services at value-added cost including flexible electronic-billing for short-term work orders involving both laboratory and manufacturing automation which can be as short as one hour of billed engagement to deliver best-in-class automation. We offer expert-level systematic testing and validation services to deliver distinguished product quality and support.

Our extensive experience delivering quality drives key performance indicators and efficiency to realize targeted performance goals demanded by the industry. Please engage with us today to gain insight about how our services and team can assist you to drive further value for your products, supply chains, and customers. Thank you again!

Sincerely,

Robert Devine

Robert Devine